{"tossups": [{"question": "This man allegedly told his executioners \u201cI hope that all of you will follow me\u201d as he was killed in Ramla. This man, who briefly lived at 14 Garibaldi Street in Buenos Aires, was attacked while bringing flowers to his wife on their silver wedding anniversary. This man lived under the alias of Ricardo Klement when he was caught by Simon Wiesenthal. Hannah Arendt coined the phrase \u201cbanality of evil\u201d to describe this man during his trial in Israel, after which he was executed in 1962. For the point, name this Nazi who organized much of the Holocaust.", "answer": "Adolf<b> Eichmann</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "In this city, the Independent Commission Against Corruption was created to prosecute the police by Murray MacLehose, who also expanded this city with \u201cNew Towns\u201d like Sha Tin that were connected by the Mass Transit Railway. The final governor of the city, Chris Patten, returned it to Jiang Zemin following the expiration of a 99-year lease of the New Territories, located north of Kowloon City. For the point, name this colony that was given to China in a 1997 handover and is now a special administrative region near Macau.", "answer": "<b> Hong Kong</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "A leader of this organization fell from power after he told James Kelso to allow an 1871 march that led to the Orange Riots. This group, which experienced a small revival in the 1950s under Carmine DeSapio, was opposed by the Locofocos in the 1830s and attacked by Samuel Tilden in the 1870s. Al Smith\u2019s political career was fueled by this group, but he did not personally gain from its corruption. This group was depicted as a loose tiger in a Thomas Nast cartoon, and Nast commonly attacked its most famous head. For the point, name this New York Democratic political machine once led by \u201cBoss\u201d Tweed.", "answer": "<b> Tammany Hall</b> (accept<b> Society</b> of Saint<b> Tammany</b> or<b> Sons of Saint Tammany</b>)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "Along this peninsula, an attack on the Moevenpick Hotel was one of several 2005 bombings conducted on one country\u2019s Revolution Day. A maneuver known as \u201cThe Crossing\u201d was an early part of a plan to take over this peninsula called Operation Badr. A 1979 treaty marked the start of one country\u2019s withdrawal from this peninsula, which contains the tourist city of Sharm el Sheikh. A biblical mountain shares its name with, for the point, what peninsula that, in the Six Day War, was taken by Israel from Egypt?", "answer": "<b> Sinai</b> Peninsula", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "The Battle of Borodino was won by, for the point, what general who was later exiled to St. Helena after losing at Waterloo?", "answer": "<b> Napoleon</b> Bonaparte (or<b> Napoleon</b> I)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "Following the wreck of the<em> San Felipe</em> in this ruler\u2019s country, he ordered the execution of a group of Christians who became known as the 26 Martyrs. This leader, who organized the Council of Five Elders to guide his young son to succeed him, confiscated weapons from peasants by ordering a sword hunt in 1588. This leader launched two failed invasions of Korea and served as a soldier under Oda Nobunaga. For the point, name this great unifier of Japan who was succeeded by Tokugawa Ieyasu.", "answer": "<b> Toyotomi</b> Hideyoshi (accept<b> Hashiba</b> Hideyoshi)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "Rodrigo Diaz de Vivar was the name of, for the point, what national hero of Spain?", "answer": "El<b> Cid</b> (accept Rodrigo Diaz de<b> Vivar</b> before it is read)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "The sitting president defended an action undertaken by this man on May Day by citing the lack of an \u201copen skies\u201d agreement between the U.S. and European powers. Nikita Khrushchev withdrew from a Four Power Summit in Paris after announcing that this man had been captured by the Soviet Union. The U.S. covered up an action taken by this man by claiming that a weather plane had veered off course in Turkey. For the point, name this U-2 spy plane pilot who was shot down in 1960.", "answer": "(Francis) Gary<b> Powers</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "Future president Franklin Roosevelt once sent a screenplay about this man\u2019s life to Paramount that was rejected by higher-ups. Catherine II said that \u201c[this man] will get to Constantinople\u201d after he entered her service during the Russo-Turkish War. When the HMS<em> Serapis</em> demanded surrender, this captain legendarily said \u201cI have not yet begun to fight!\u201d. For the point, name this \u201cFather of the American Navy,\u201dthe captain of the<em> Bonhomme Richard</em>.", "answer": "John Paul<b> Jones</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "Early in the reign of this dynasty,<em> Bamboo Groves in Mist and Rain</em> was painted by artist and poet Guan Daosheng. Wang Meng, one of this dynasty\u2019s Four Great Masters of landscape painting, refused to serve this dynasty\u2019s ruling ethnic group. This dynasty named Taizu its honorary first emperor, although it was founded by his grandson, Kublai. For the point, name this Chinese dynasty visited by Marco Polo and founded by the Mongols.", "answer": "<b> Yuan</b> Dynasty (accept Da<b> Yuan</b>)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "The American Colonization Society helped establish, for the point, what African country that was founded by American freed slaves?", "answer": "Republic of<b> Liberia</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "These people were targeted in Logrono after many of them met at places called akelarres. Johann Weyer wrote that these people had mental illnesses but were harmless. Jakob Sprenger and Heinrich Kramer wrote a work titled for the \u201cHammer of\u201d these people that suggested the use of cold water to find them. Thousands of these people, who were believed to not sink in water, died in a \u201ccraze\u201d in the 1600s. For the point, name these people who supposedly practiced black magic and were subjected to hunts in cities like Salem.", "answer": "<b> witch</b>es", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "This city\u2019s citizens were picked up in the<em> Blue Ridge</em> after ambassador Graham Martin convinced the ship to stay behind. The song \u201cWhite Christmas\u201d signaled the evacuation of this city during Operation Frequent Wind, sparking a mass exodus of refugees called \u201cboat people.\u201d The loss of this city was celebrated as \u201cReunification Day\u201d in the North after the withdrawal of all American personnel. For the point, name this city that was renamed for Ho Chi Minh following the Vietnam War.", "answer": "<b> Saigon</b> (accept<b> Ho Chi Minh City</b> before \u201cHo\u201d is read)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "This composer used a repeating A-flat in the left hand to depict nasty weather while on a trip to Majorca [my-yor-kah]. The poetry of Adam Mickiewicz [meetz-keh-vitch] inspired this composer\u2019s four <em>Ballades</em> [bah-LAHDS], and this composer wrote a G-flat major work featuring 16th-note triplets on just the black keys of the piano. The 1830 November Uprising inspired the<em> Revolutionary</em>\u00b4Etude by, for the point, what Romantic composer whose mazurkas and polonaises were inspired by his home country, Poland?", "answer": "Fr\u00b4ed\u00b4eric (Fran\u00b8cois)<b> Chopin</b>", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Auditory Fine Arts"}, {"question": "Following a battle in this war, a monarch fled into the protection of Sultan Ahmed III and sparked the Pruth River Campaign. Johann Patkul engineered this war by creating an alliance with the Treaty of Preobrazhenskoye after fleeing to the court of Augustus the Strong. Despite early victories at Travendal and Narva, Charles XII was crushed at Poltava in this war. For the point, name this early 18th century war in which Peter the Great elevated Russia to a great power by crushing the Swedish Empire.", "answer": "<b> Great Northern</b> War", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {}, {"question": "In Norse mythology, one of these creatures advises Sigurd to dig trenches to avoid drowning in a deluge of blood; that creature, Fafnir, was a dwarf who became one of these creatures after hoarding gold. One of these creatures kills and is killed by Beowulf and another of these creatures is killed by the patron saint of England. Costumes of lions and these creatures are used by dancers during Chinese New Year festivities. Saint George legendarily slew, for the point, what type of flying reptile from mythology?", "answer": "<b> dragon</b> (prompt on serpent or snake)", "metadata": "Mythology - Mythology"}, {"question": "The SALT II [\u201csalt two\u201d] treaty was signed by this President, who then pulled it from consideration by the Senate after the Soviet invasion of Afghanistan. This President created the Department of Energy to counter an oil crisis that prompted him to claim America was facing a \u201ccrisis of confidence\u201d in the\u201cMalaise\u201d speech. This man facilitated the Camp David Accords but failed to end the Iran Hostage Crisis, leading him to lose the election of 1980 to Ronald Reagan. For the point, name this 39th US President, a former peanut farmer from Georgia.", "answer": "James Earl \u201cJimmy\u201d<b> Carter</b> Jr.", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "This novel\u2019s narrator remembers how his mother said \u201cThe Lord\u2019s will be done\u201d and continued to milk a cow when she heard that he had enlisted in the army. After receiving a head wound, the main character of this novel witnesses the death of the Tall Soldier, Jim Conklin. This novel, which is set during the Battle of Chancellorsville, is about the inexperienced private Henry Fleming. For the point, name this Civil War novel by Stephen Crane.", "answer": "The<b> Red Badge of Courage</b>", "metadata": "Literature - American Literature - Short Fiction"}, {"question": "This man married Stateira II, the captured daughter of a rival who Bessus assassinated after losing to this man. This ruler fought against war elephants in King Porus\u2019s army at the Hydaspes River. The Diadochi fought over this man\u2019s empire after he died in Babylon shortly after turning his armies back from India. Darius III was beaten at Gaugamela and Issus by, for the point, what son of Philip II who ruled Macedonia and a massive ancient empire?", "answer": "<b> Alexander the Great</b> (or<b> Alexander III</b> of Macedon; prompt on Alexander)", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {}, {"question": "A Republican politician from this state led the Half-Breeds and lost the 1884 presidential election; that man was James G. Blaine. The ability of local elections in this state to predict the result of national elections gave rise to the saying \u201cAs\u201d this state \u201cgoes, so goes the nation.\u201d This state and Nebraska are the only two states that can currently split their votes in the Electoral College. Susan Collins has won four Senate elections in, for the point, what New England state with capital Augusta?", "answer": "<b> Maine</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "The largest of these ships built during World War II was destroyed by the<em> Archerfish</em> and was named <em>Shinano</em>. Those who allege that the US government had advance knowledge of the Pearl Harbor attack point out that these ships were not in the harbor at the time. The sinking of four Japanese ships of this type by the US Navy was a decisive factor in the Battle of Midway. For the point, name this type of warship that can act as a base for planes.", "answer": "aircraft<b> carrier</b>s <b>Extra Question</b> Only read if moderator botches a question.", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "This woman\u2019s husband Prasutagus attempted to leave his kingdom jointly to his daughters and the Roman Emperor, but the Romans rejected that will and whipped her instead. After Suetonius became engaged in fighting in the far west, this woman launched a massive rebellion in which Camulodunum and Londinium were burned. The Battle of Watling Street ended the revolt led by, for the point, what first century AD queen of the Iceni who opposed Roman rule in Britain?", "answer": "<b> Boudica</b> (or<b> Boadicea</b>)", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}], "bonuses": []}